{"value":"1 JMIR Cancer 2023 Apr 28;9 e37330 doi 10.2196/37330   Features Cancer mHealth Apps Evidence Patient Preferences Scoping   Literature Review   Vaffis S(1 Whaley S(1 Axon DR(1 Hall Lipsy E(1 Hincapie A(2 Slack   M(1 Warholak T(1   Author information 1)College Pharmacy University Arizona Tucson AZ United States 2)James L Winkle College Pharmacy University Cincinnati Cincinnati OH   United States   BACKGROUND Cancer increasingly treated chronic disease   acute time illness Additionally oral anticancer therapies   opposed intravenous chemotherapy available increasing number   cancer indications Mobile health mHealth apps use mobile devices   eg smartphones tablets designed help patients medication   adherence symptom tracking disease management previous literature   reviews conducted mHealth apps cancer   studies address patient preferences features cancer mHealth   apps OBJECTIVE primary aim review scientific literature   describes features functions mHealth apps designed cancer   self management METHODS purpose review explore depth breadth   research mHealth app features cancer self management scoping review   methodology adopted databases review   PubMed MEDLINE Embase CINAHL PsycINFO Citation reference searches   conducted manuscripts meeting inclusion criteria gray literature   search conducted Data   extracted manuscripts   included author   title publication date study type sampling type cancer type treatment age   participants features availability free subscription design input   patient preferences Finally features listed app   compared highlighting similarities platforms features unique   app RESULTS removal duplicates 522 manuscripts remained title   abstract review 51 undergoing text review total 7   manuscripts referred studies included final   scoping review App features described study varied 2 11   median 4 features app reported feature symptom   effect tracker reported 6 studies apps specified   inclusion patients health care providers design 1 app   noted communications experts provided design input utility   apps end users measured ways including acceptability   measuring end users experience usability assessing functionality   performance observing real users completing tasks qualitative data   reports end users collected interviews focus groups CONCLUSIONS review explored literature cancer mHealth apps Popular   features mHealth apps include symptom trackers cancer education   medication trackers apps features developed   little input patients Additionally little information   patient preferences features existing apps   number cancer related apps available download continues increase   exploration patient preferences app features result apps   better meet patient disease self management needs   © Shannon Vaffis Soluna Whaley David Rhys Axon Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana   Hincapie Marion Slack Terri Warholak Originally published JMIR Cancer   https://cancer.jmir.org 28.04.2023   DOI 10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","entities":[{"text":"1","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"2023","label":"DATE"},{"text":"10.2196/37330","label":"ORDINAL"},{"text":"Features Cancer","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Arizona","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Tucson","label":"GPE"},{"text":"AZ United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"L Winkle College Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Mobile","label":"ORG"},{"text":"RESULTS","label":"ORG"},{"text":"522","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"51","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"7","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"App","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"2 11","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"4","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"6","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"1 app","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"ORG"},{"text":"David Rhys Axon","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"JMIR Cancer","label":"PRODUCT"},{"text":"28.04.2023","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","label":"DATE"}]}
{"value":"1 JMIR Cancer 2023 Apr 28;9 e37330 doi 10.2196/37330   Features Cancer mHealth Apps Evidence Patient Preferences Scoping   Literature Review   Vaffis S(1 Whaley S(1 Axon DR(1 Hall Lipsy E(1 Hincapie A(2 Slack   M(1 Warholak T(1   Author information 1)College Pharmacy University Arizona Tucson AZ United States 2)James L Winkle College Pharmacy University Cincinnati Cincinnati OH   United States   BACKGROUND Cancer increasingly treated chronic disease   acute time illness Additionally oral anticancer therapies   opposed intravenous chemotherapy available increasing number   cancer indications Mobile health mHealth apps use mobile devices   eg smartphones tablets designed help patients medication   adherence symptom tracking disease management previous literature   reviews conducted mHealth apps cancer   studies address patient preferences features cancer mHealth   apps OBJECTIVE primary aim review scientific literature   describes features functions mHealth apps designed cancer   self management METHODS purpose review explore depth breadth   research mHealth app features cancer self management scoping review   methodology adopted databases review   PubMed MEDLINE Embase CINAHL PsycINFO Citation reference searches   conducted manuscripts meeting inclusion criteria gray literature   search conducted Data   extracted manuscripts   included author   title publication date study type sampling type cancer type treatment age   participants features availability free subscription design input   patient preferences Finally features listed app   compared highlighting similarities platforms features unique   app RESULTS removal duplicates 522 manuscripts remained title   abstract review 51 undergoing text review total 7   manuscripts referred studies included final   scoping review App features described study varied 2 11   median 4 features app reported feature symptom   effect tracker reported 6 studies apps specified   inclusion patients health care providers design 1 app   noted communications experts provided design input utility   apps end users measured ways including acceptability   measuring end users experience usability assessing functionality   performance observing real users completing tasks qualitative data   reports end users collected interviews focus groups CONCLUSIONS review explored literature cancer mHealth apps Popular   features mHealth apps include symptom trackers cancer education   medication trackers apps features developed   little input patients Additionally little information   patient preferences features existing apps   number cancer related apps available download continues increase   exploration patient preferences app features result apps   better meet patient disease self management needs   © Shannon Vaffis Soluna Whaley David Rhys Axon Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana   Hincapie Marion Slack Terri Warholak Originally published JMIR Cancer   https://cancer.jmir.org 28.04.2023   DOI 10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","entities":[{"text":"1","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"2023","label":"DATE"},{"text":"10.2196/37330","label":"ORDINAL"},{"text":"Features Cancer","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Arizona","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Tucson","label":"GPE"},{"text":"AZ United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"L Winkle College Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Mobile","label":"ORG"},{"text":"RESULTS","label":"ORG"},{"text":"522","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"51","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"7","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"App","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"2 11","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"4","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"6","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"1 app","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"ORG"},{"text":"David Rhys Axon","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"JMIR Cancer","label":"PRODUCT"},{"text":"28.04.2023","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","label":"DATE"}]}
{"value":"1 JMIR Cancer 2023 Apr 28;9 e37330 doi 10.2196/37330   Features Cancer mHealth Apps Evidence Patient Preferences Scoping   Literature Review   Vaffis S(1 Whaley S(1 Axon DR(1 Hall Lipsy E(1 Hincapie A(2 Slack   M(1 Warholak T(1   Author information 1)College Pharmacy University Arizona Tucson AZ United States 2)James L Winkle College Pharmacy University Cincinnati Cincinnati OH   United States   BACKGROUND Cancer increasingly treated chronic disease   acute time illness Additionally oral anticancer therapies   opposed intravenous chemotherapy available increasing number   cancer indications Mobile health mHealth apps use mobile devices   eg smartphones tablets designed help patients medication   adherence symptom tracking disease management previous literature   reviews conducted mHealth apps cancer   studies address patient preferences features cancer mHealth   apps OBJECTIVE primary aim review scientific literature   describes features functions mHealth apps designed cancer   self management METHODS purpose review explore depth breadth   research mHealth app features cancer self management scoping review   methodology adopted databases review   PubMed MEDLINE Embase CINAHL PsycINFO Citation reference searches   conducted manuscripts meeting inclusion criteria gray literature   search conducted Data   extracted manuscripts   included author   title publication date study type sampling type cancer type treatment age   participants features availability free subscription design input   patient preferences Finally features listed app   compared highlighting similarities platforms features unique   app RESULTS removal duplicates 522 manuscripts remained title   abstract review 51 undergoing text review total 7   manuscripts referred studies included final   scoping review App features described study varied 2 11   median 4 features app reported feature symptom   effect tracker reported 6 studies apps specified   inclusion patients health care providers design 1 app   noted communications experts provided design input utility   apps end users measured ways including acceptability   measuring end users experience usability assessing functionality   performance observing real users completing tasks qualitative data   reports end users collected interviews focus groups CONCLUSIONS review explored literature cancer mHealth apps Popular   features mHealth apps include symptom trackers cancer education   medication trackers apps features developed   little input patients Additionally little information   patient preferences features existing apps   number cancer related apps available download continues increase   exploration patient preferences app features result apps   better meet patient disease self management needs   © Shannon Vaffis Soluna Whaley David Rhys Axon Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana   Hincapie Marion Slack Terri Warholak Originally published JMIR Cancer   https://cancer.jmir.org 28.04.2023   DOI 10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","entities":[{"text":"1","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"2023","label":"DATE"},{"text":"10.2196/37330","label":"ORDINAL"},{"text":"Features Cancer","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Arizona","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Tucson","label":"GPE"},{"text":"AZ United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"L Winkle College Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Mobile","label":"ORG"},{"text":"RESULTS","label":"ORG"},{"text":"522","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"51","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"7","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"App","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"2 11","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"4","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"6","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"1 app","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"ORG"},{"text":"David Rhys Axon","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"JMIR Cancer","label":"PRODUCT"},{"text":"28.04.2023","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","label":"DATE"}]}
{"value":"1 JMIR Cancer 2023 Apr 28;9 e37330 doi 10.2196/37330   Features Cancer mHealth Apps Evidence Patient Preferences Scoping   Literature Review   Vaffis S(1 Whaley S(1 Axon DR(1 Hall Lipsy E(1 Hincapie A(2 Slack   M(1 Warholak T(1   Author information 1)College Pharmacy University Arizona Tucson AZ United States 2)James L Winkle College Pharmacy University Cincinnati Cincinnati OH   United States   BACKGROUND Cancer increasingly treated chronic disease   acute time illness Additionally oral anticancer therapies   opposed intravenous chemotherapy available increasing number   cancer indications Mobile health mHealth apps use mobile devices   eg smartphones tablets designed help patients medication   adherence symptom tracking disease management previous literature   reviews conducted mHealth apps cancer   studies address patient preferences features cancer mHealth   apps OBJECTIVE primary aim review scientific literature   describes features functions mHealth apps designed cancer   self management METHODS purpose review explore depth breadth   research mHealth app features cancer self management scoping review   methodology adopted databases review   PubMed MEDLINE Embase CINAHL PsycINFO Citation reference searches   conducted manuscripts meeting inclusion criteria gray literature   search conducted Data   extracted manuscripts   included author   title publication date study type sampling type cancer type treatment age   participants features availability free subscription design input   patient preferences Finally features listed app   compared highlighting similarities platforms features unique   app RESULTS removal duplicates 522 manuscripts remained title   abstract review 51 undergoing text review total 7   manuscripts referred studies included final   scoping review App features described study varied 2 11   median 4 features app reported feature symptom   effect tracker reported 6 studies apps specified   inclusion patients health care providers design 1 app   noted communications experts provided design input utility   apps end users measured ways including acceptability   measuring end users experience usability assessing functionality   performance observing real users completing tasks qualitative data   reports end users collected interviews focus groups CONCLUSIONS review explored literature cancer mHealth apps Popular   features mHealth apps include symptom trackers cancer education   medication trackers apps features developed   little input patients Additionally little information   patient preferences features existing apps   number cancer related apps available download continues increase   exploration patient preferences app features result apps   better meet patient disease self management needs   © Shannon Vaffis Soluna Whaley David Rhys Axon Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana   Hincapie Marion Slack Terri Warholak Originally published JMIR Cancer   https://cancer.jmir.org 28.04.2023   DOI 10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","entities":[{"text":"1","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"2023","label":"DATE"},{"text":"10.2196/37330","label":"ORDINAL"},{"text":"Features Cancer","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Arizona","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Tucson","label":"GPE"},{"text":"AZ United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"L Winkle College Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Mobile","label":"ORG"},{"text":"RESULTS","label":"ORG"},{"text":"522","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"51","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"7","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"App","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"2 11","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"4","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"6","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"1 app","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"ORG"},{"text":"David Rhys Axon","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"JMIR Cancer","label":"PRODUCT"},{"text":"28.04.2023","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","label":"DATE"}]}
{"value":"1 JMIR Cancer 2023 Apr 28;9 e37330 doi 10.2196/37330   Features Cancer mHealth Apps Evidence Patient Preferences Scoping   Literature Review   Vaffis S(1 Whaley S(1 Axon DR(1 Hall Lipsy E(1 Hincapie A(2 Slack   M(1 Warholak T(1   Author information 1)College Pharmacy University Arizona Tucson AZ United States 2)James L Winkle College Pharmacy University Cincinnati Cincinnati OH   United States   BACKGROUND Cancer increasingly treated chronic disease   acute time illness Additionally oral anticancer therapies   opposed intravenous chemotherapy available increasing number   cancer indications Mobile health mHealth apps use mobile devices   eg smartphones tablets designed help patients medication   adherence symptom tracking disease management previous literature   reviews conducted mHealth apps cancer   studies address patient preferences features cancer mHealth   apps OBJECTIVE primary aim review scientific literature   describes features functions mHealth apps designed cancer   self management METHODS purpose review explore depth breadth   research mHealth app features cancer self management scoping review   methodology adopted databases review   PubMed MEDLINE Embase CINAHL PsycINFO Citation reference searches   conducted manuscripts meeting inclusion criteria gray literature   search conducted Data   extracted manuscripts   included author   title publication date study type sampling type cancer type treatment age   participants features availability free subscription design input   patient preferences Finally features listed app   compared highlighting similarities platforms features unique   app RESULTS removal duplicates 522 manuscripts remained title   abstract review 51 undergoing text review total 7   manuscripts referred studies included final   scoping review App features described study varied 2 11   median 4 features app reported feature symptom   effect tracker reported 6 studies apps specified   inclusion patients health care providers design 1 app   noted communications experts provided design input utility   apps end users measured ways including acceptability   measuring end users experience usability assessing functionality   performance observing real users completing tasks qualitative data   reports end users collected interviews focus groups CONCLUSIONS review explored literature cancer mHealth apps Popular   features mHealth apps include symptom trackers cancer education   medication trackers apps features developed   little input patients Additionally little information   patient preferences features existing apps   number cancer related apps available download continues increase   exploration patient preferences app features result apps   better meet patient disease self management needs   © Shannon Vaffis Soluna Whaley David Rhys Axon Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana   Hincapie Marion Slack Terri Warholak Originally published JMIR Cancer   https://cancer.jmir.org 28.04.2023   DOI 10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","entities":[{"text":"1","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"2023","label":"DATE"},{"text":"10.2196/37330","label":"ORDINAL"},{"text":"Features Cancer","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Arizona","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Tucson","label":"GPE"},{"text":"AZ United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"L Winkle College Pharmacy University","label":"ORG"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Cincinnati","label":"GPE"},{"text":"United States","label":"GPE"},{"text":"Mobile","label":"ORG"},{"text":"RESULTS","label":"ORG"},{"text":"522","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"51","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"7","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"App","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"2 11","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"4","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"6","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"1 app","label":"QUANTITY"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"apps","label":"ORG"},{"text":"David Rhys Axon","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"Elizabeth Hall Lipsy Ana","label":"PERSON"},{"text":"JMIR Cancer","label":"PRODUCT"},{"text":"28.04.2023","label":"CARDINAL"},{"text":"10.2196/37330 PMID 37115587","label":"DATE"}]}
